I eat vegetables
我有吃蔬菜啊
I have eaten fruit
我有吃水果啊
You asked me to eat the whole stock, and I also ate it.
你叫我吃全股我也有吃啊
You said protein, I also eat
你說蛋白質我也吃啦
Then why is my health not as good as yours
那為什麼我的健康就沒你的好
that difference
那個差別
That small difference means
那個小小的差別就是說
Now this bento has too few vegetables
現在這個便當蔬菜太少
not enough protein
蛋白質不夠
what is rice
飯怎麼是白飯
So I'm going to correct it
所以我會去校正啊
i go home at night
我晚上回家
I just eat back the vegetables I don't have enough
我就把我不夠的蔬菜吃回來了
The fruit I didn't have enough also came back
我不夠的水果也吃回來了
Then he gave me rice
然後他給我白飯
bring some of that
自己帶一點那個
Wheat with Sprouts for Sprinkling
小麥配芽粉撒上去
I'll just make a small change
我就做一點小小的改變
Your body is different from others
你的身體就跟人家不一樣
Another aspect of vitality is weakness
活力的另一個面向就是衰弱
this weakness and incapacity
這個衰弱與失能
and geriatric syndrome
以及老年症候群呢
this phenomenon
這個現象
so you might be clearer
所以你可能就會比較清楚
how to make quotation
怎麼樣能夠讓引法
Enough to live with such vitality
足得還活出這樣一個活力來
That's another
那另外就是
compare against us
針對我們比較
There may be some younger
可能有一些比較年輕的
Learn about the aging process
可以了解一下老化過程中
Changes in our bodies and our bodies
我們身體跟身體的改變
younger after middle age
中年後更年輕
you can think at this time
你都可以在這個時候來思考
how do i keep healthy
我怎麼樣保健
So I'll come to Citation in the future
所以我以後到引法中
I can be at my best
我能夠在一個最佳的狀態
Frailty and disability and geriatric syndrome
衰弱與失能以及老年症候群
Let me tell you about us alone
要先跟大家講一下我們一個人
How do we humans enter into a disability
我們人是怎麼樣進入一個失能
or a weakened state
或一個衰弱的狀態
And this incapacity and weakness
而這個失能和衰弱
what kind of relationship
是什麼樣的一個關係
So you know what we're talking about today
所以大家知道我們今天講的
geriatric syndrome
這個老年症候群
In fact, it is not a person in his fifties or sixties.
其實它並不是五六十歲的人
problems encountered
所碰到的問題
that you have been very healthy all your life
就是你一生都非常健康
no cardiovascular disease
沒有心臟血管疾病
nothing sick
什麼病都沒有
a situation you will also encounter
你也會碰到的一個狀況
This diagram shows that one of us
這個圖顯示出我們一個人的
a state of aging
老化的一個狀態
The one who maintains better is this red thread
那維持著更好的人是這個紅線
stay level all the time
一直都保持水平的狀態
But if a person with a lot of pain
但是如果一個病痛比較多的人
He's always following this curve
他走的是往往是這條曲線
In other words, his function declined rapidly.
也就是說他的功能下降得很快
not too old
不是太年紀大的時候
into a state of weakness
而就進入了衰弱的狀態
So because he is in a weakened state
所以因為他在衰弱的狀態
It is easy to re-enter incapacitation
就很容易的再進入了失能
to this final stage of life
走到人生的這個最終的一個階段
stay as strong as possible
盡可能的能夠保持健壯
active state
有活力的狀態
Then stay at that red line up to the max
然後在那個紅線維持到最高
This time of life maintains a final stage
人生的這個時間維持在一個最終的階段
peak state
高峰的狀態
good month long month
月久月好
Then if what is going to drop is in a very short time
那如果要掉落的是在很短時間內
if it falls like this
假如這樣子掉落
has entered a state of weakness
已經進入了衰弱的狀態
can you still reply
你是不是還能回復呢
actually it is possible
其實是可以的
you can still work hard
你還是可以努力
Let your function curve
讓你的這一條功能曲線
come back to the top
回到上面來
Those who rub a little don't be discouraged
稍微擦的人不要氣餒
ok can use some
好 可以用一些
way of life style of life
方式生活型態的方式
let you reply
讓你回復
Then you walk in a
然後你又走在一個
very good one
非常好的一個
on the road to health
健康的一個道路上
That frailty is often associated with chronic disease
那衰弱症常常和慢性病
are closely related
是息息相關的
may cause disability
可能會導致失能
observed an old man
觀察到一個老人
Usually we say that it is not good for people to be fat
通常我們說人太胖不好
But if you are already fat
但是如果是已經胖的體質
If you observe a fat old man
你如果觀察到一個胖胖的老人
suddenly lost weight
突然瘦了
just a warning sign
就是一個警訊
It's a warning sign of weakness
就是衰弱的警訊
sudden weight loss
體重突然的減輕
often feel exhausted
常常覺得筋疲力盡
hand grip is strong enough
手的握力很夠
I have no strength to hold things
拿東西沒有力氣
I don't want to go out
不想出去動了
I was going for a walk
本來散步的
no more walks now
現在也不散步了
I don't do some things normally
平常做一些事都不做了
walking?
走路呢
slower and slower
速度越來越慢
These phenomena are called asthenia
這幾個現象就是所謂的衰弱症
Basically this is a
基本上這個就是一個
Elderly Health Issues
老年健康的問題
so i'm talking about
所以我現在談的是
It's really full of problems behind
真的是滿後面的問題
but i think
但是我想
People in their fifties and sixties
五六十歲的人
should start to understand
應該要開始了解
solve the problem
解之問題
Even people in their thirties and forties
那甚至三四十歲的人
you can also follow
你也可以關注
It can also help your own family
也可以幫助自己家的
old man inside
裡面的老人
Weak hand grip
手握力過弱
walking too slowly
步行速度過慢
weight loss
體重下降
always feel tired
總是感覺疲憊
decreased physical activity
身體的活動降低了
I don't have the strength and don't want to go out to do it
沒有力氣也不想出去做
three is called weakness
有三個就叫做衰弱
then one or two words
那麼一到兩個的話
pre-frailty
是所謂衰弱前期
In fact, people over the age of sixty-five
其實六十五歲以上的老人
we look like this
我們這樣看起來
That is, 60% of them already have
就是六成都已經有
A phenomenon of more than one weakening
一個以上的一個衰弱的一個現象
This course of debilitation develops
衰弱的這個病程發展
generally considered
一般是認為
genetic and environmental factors
跟遺傳因素環境因素
It's all related
都有關係的
And these factors
而這些因素的
other common interactions
其他共同的交互作用
will cause some of our body
會造成我們身體的一些
cell damage
細胞的損傷
or a lesion at some molecular level
或者一些分子層次的一個損傷
This damage affects
這損傷就影響到
multiple system organs
多重的系統器官的
drop in some functionality
一些功能的下降
Contains the brain
包含腦
endocrine
內分泌
immunity
免疫
muscle heart
肌肉心臟
Blood vessel
血管
breathing kidney etc.
呼吸腎臟等等
after this drop
在這個下降之後
If not properly such
如果沒有妥當的這樣的
a lifestyle
一個生活型態
good nutrition
好的營養
and with
以及用
Proper physical activity to maintain your body's muscles
適當的體能活動來保持自己的身體的肌肉
and cell function
和細胞的功能的話
It is easy to develop symptoms of decline
就很容易發展到衰落的症狀
This is what I just mentioned
這個就是我剛剛提到
when accidents happen
當意外事件發生的時候
Metabolic Syndrome
就很深奧的代謝症候群
I think old people just shouldn't eat too much protein
我認為老人就是不該吃太多的蛋白質
The burden on the kidneys is too heavy
腎臟負擔太重
but i know
但是我就知道
This means that many people have such a concept
這表示說很多人都有這樣的一個概念
That is to say, the elderly should not eat too much protein
就是說老人不該吃太多的蛋白質
May be physically taxing
可能會對身體有負擔
Then I want to tell you that
那我要跟大家講就是說
current scientific literature
現在的科學文獻
Is supporting protein and burning medicine officially
是支持蛋白質和燒藥正式
interrelated
互相相關的
It's probably an egg balancing study
它多半是用一種蛋平衡研究
that is, discussing a person
就是說探討一個人
how much protein do i give him
我給他多少的蛋白質
and see how much he excretes
然後看他排泄多少
Take one more point and the balance will be reached
再拿一個點會達到平衡
Most of these studies
多半是這樣的研究
Of course there are now
當然現在還有
So in order to understand
所以我們為了要了解
How much protein do Taiwanese need to eat?
台灣人到底要吃多少蛋白質呢
This method is to say
這個方法就是說
AI for Nutrients
了解營養素的AI
AI is the so-called appropriate intake
AI就是所謂的適當攝取量
this is a method
這是一個方法
This method is acceptable in nutrition
這個方法是在營養學裡是可接受的
it means
它意思就是說
If you do not have the appropriate data
你如果沒有適當的數據的時候
you just grade
你就是去評分
those who have no problem at all
那些完全沒有問題人
how much does he eat
他到底吃多少
Thoughts on this nutrition survey
這個營養調查的思維
let's do the math
我們來做一下計算
We just divide the elderly into
我們就是把老年人把它分成
non-attenuated attenuated preamplifier and attenuated
非衰弱衰弱前級跟衰弱
to see
來看
Just look at the data on the right.
大家就看這個右邊的數據就好了
These elderly people without debilitating diseases
沒有衰弱症的這些老人
what is his protein intake
他的蛋白質攝取量是多少呢
we see yes
我們看到是
1.21 per kilogram of body weight
每公斤體重1.21
1.22 for men and women
男性 女性是1.22
This is a mesogastric
這是一個中胃素
What does mesogastric mean?
中胃素是什麼意思呢
is the most people
就是最多的人
people here
這裡面的人
Most of these people are uptake
最屈中的這些人都是攝取量
we can see the debilitated
我們可以看到衰弱的人
Eat less than one gram per kilogram of body weight a day
是一天一公斤體重吃不到一克
Pre-failure is centered
衰弱前期是居中
Then this number may not mean anything to you
那這個數目可能對大家沒有什麼
Maybe you see this number and feel nothing
可能你看到這個數也覺得沒什麼
but i want to tell you
但是我要跟大家講
Global Recommendations for Protein
全球對於蛋白質的建議
almost all have a number
幾乎都有一個數目
That number is 1.2
那個數目就是1.2
an old man a day
一個老人一天
He needs to eat 1.2 grams per kilogram of body weight
他每公斤體重要吃1.2克
you can eat like this
你怎樣吃就可以吃到這個樣子
The American-Japanese Diet Guide
這個美日飲食指南
it is calculated after semen
它是經過精液的計算
That is, if you keep eating
就是你如果照著吃的話
All your nutrients will be up to standard
你的各種營養素都是會達標的
But among
可是當中
When middle-aged people are doing this
中年在做这个东西的时候呢
No one knows that the old man Meigong needs to eat 1.2 grams
没有人知道老人美工精体重要吃1.2克
19 to 34 years old
19到34岁了
If he eats such 1850 calories
如果他吃到这样1850大卡
Or he eats 2150 to above
或他吃到2150到以上
Is his agent worth enough?
他的代卖值够不够
Enough 1kg 1.2g is really difficult to produce
够的1公斤1.2克真的难生了
Even a 71-year-old
即便到71岁的老人
If he eats 1650 calories he will be enough
如果他吃1650大卡他也够
But we found that
可是我们发现就是说
What if it's on the women's side?
如果在女性这一边的话呢
From young women he has some who eat very little
从年轻女性他就有一些人吃很少
1450 calories only
1450大卡而已
Some women in their 70s
到了老年70几岁有些女性
Only eat 1300 calories
只吃到1300大卡
So for those who are older and eat less
所以对于这些年纪大又吃得少的人
His sales value is not enough
他的这个代卖值是不够的
Usually there is a general rule
平常都是有一个通则
That is if you eat very little people
就是说如果你吃很少的人
you are prone to malnutrition
你很容易营养不良
If the entrusted sales value is not enough, it will enter into decline
代卖值会不够就会进入衰弱
this stage
这个阶段
talk to the government
跟政府讲说
you for people who eat less
你对于吃得比较少的人的
This dietary advice needs to be modified
这个饮食建议要做修改
otherwise
不然的话
These people may fall into the proxy for insufficient value
这些人可能会落入代卖值不足
Especially the camp French
就是特别是营法族这一块
Internationally, the most concerned is consignment sales
国际上最关注的就是代卖
to address the weakness
來針對衰弱這一點
Frailty is not only related to protein
衰弱症除了和蛋白質有關
Is it not related to other nutrients?
難道和其他的營養素沒有關係嗎
We found in the literature
我們發現在文獻上
I saw that it is related to many trace elements
就看到說它跟很多的微量元素都是相關的
And it seems that there is a phenomenon that
而且好像有個現象就是
Nutrient deficient items
營養素缺乏的項目
more words
越多的話
the greater the chance that the person is debilitated
這個人是罹患衰弱症的這個機會就越大
other than protein
除了蛋白質以外
lack of literature
文獻素低的缺乏
B12 deficiency
文獻素B12的缺乏
lack of C
C的缺乏
new lack
新的缺乏
have some correlation
都有一些相關性
One conjecture might be that
一個推測可能就是說
Is it just eating too little?
是不是就是吃了太少
So let's explore further
所以我們又進一步的來探討一下
If an old man in Taiwan has debilitating disease,
台灣老人他如果有衰弱症的話
his overall diet
他的整體的飲食形態
what is it like
到底是一個什麼樣子
then let me tell you
那我來跟大家說一下
This is male data
這個是男性的數據
people with different heat
那不同的熱量的人
he is different
他就有不同的其實
Six categories of this proposal
六大類的這個建議
What are the six categories of recommendations?
什麼叫六大類建議呢
Usually when making dietary advice
一般在做飲食建議的時候
or divide food into six broad categories
或把食物分成六個大類
It means that you have to eat these six categories
意思就是說這六大類你都要吃
And your six categories of food
而你這六大類的食物
If you eat the portion I suggest you
你都吃到我建議你的份量的話
You have enough nutrients
你什麼營養素都是夠的
What about when your calories are low?
那么当你的热量少的时候呢
Your six categories of advice are less
你的六大类建议就比较少
Then the whole stock here is our staple food.
那这边事向全股就是我们的主食类
That is to say, it is suggested that three bowls of rice may be enough
就是说建议可能三碗饭就够了
But we noticed that these poor people eat a lot
但是我们注意到这些衰肉人他饭吃的多
He only needs three bowls
他只要是三碗就够
But he ate three and a half bowls a day
但是他吃了三碗半一天
A normal person eats a little less than what he should eat
正常人他饭来稍微的少于他该吃的份量
But everyone sees this bean fish meat egg
但是大家看到这个豆鱼肉蛋
the protein
就是所谓那个蛋白质类
All kinds of meat, eggs, seafood
各种肉啊蛋啊海鲜
This poor man also eats less
这个衰肉人也吃的少
Normally, it is the same as the early stage of degeneration
正常跟这个衰肉前期的
He is simply over the amount
他根本就超过量
But are they too much protein?
但是是不是他们的蛋白质过多呢
Actually they don't have much protein
其实他们蛋白质没有过多
Another important source of protein is milk
因为蛋白质还有一个重要的来源就是奶类
Then our people don't drink milk
那我们国人都不喝奶
So there's a bunch of protein and a lid missing here.
所以这边就缺了一堆的蛋白质还有盖子
So we can see that
所以我们可以看到就是说
If you are a person without decay
如果你是一个没有衰肉人
Actually your protein is just right
其实你的蛋白质是刚刚好的
The amount to eat is to put milk and this silicon together, it is just right
吃的量就是把奶类和这个硅在一起是刚刚好
Almost all Taiwanese
台湾人几乎都缺盖
So our bone Su Song is a big problem
所以我们骨子苏松是一大问题
For this male of these people
那这些人的这个男性来讲
less vegetables
蔬菜也少
Then the fruit didn't meet the standard
然后水果都没有达标
And there is not enough fat
还有就是油脂也不够
Because most of us young people have too much fat
因为我们一般年轻人都是油脂太多了
but these old people
可是这些老人
But the fat did not reach
卻油脂都沒有達到
this grease
這個油脂
The recommended amount of oil in Taiwan
台灣的油脂建議量
the so-called five
所謂的五份
very little
非常的少
But the reason none of them reach is because
但他們都沒有達到的原因是
Old people dare not eat too much oil
老人都不敢吃太油
So it doesn't have enough calories
所以它的熱量也不夠
so you can see
所以可以看到
A Diet for Frailty
衰弱症的一個飲食
just a little too much rice
就是飯稍微太多
Not enough eye protein
眼蛋白質不夠
not enough milk
牛奶也不夠
male words
男性的話
It seems that the vegetables and fruits are not enough
好像蔬菜水果也不夠
low fat
油脂都偏少
so is a
所以是一個
all kinds of things are not enough
各種東西都不太夠的
one case
一個情況下
Well, women have a similar trend
那麼女性有一個類似的趨勢
women we see
女性我們看到
is its heat
就是它的熱量
not that much of a difference
並沒有那麼大的一個差異
it's basically
它基本上都是
Eat much less than men
比男人吃的少很多
weak women too
衰弱的女性也是
she almost ate
她差不多吃個
80% full meal
八分滿的飯
Three bowls is about the same
三碗就是差不多
two points
二點
Two point four bowls are enough
二點四碗就夠了
But she eats almost three bowls of rice
但她吃快到三碗飯
It also has less protein
它的蛋白質也比較少
I don't drink this milk
這個奶類都不喝
fruit with little fat
水果很少油脂
rare
很少
Vegetables are eaten more
蔬菜是吃得比較多的
can feel
可以感覺到
is protein
就是蛋白質
indeed a key
確實是一個關鍵
Especially the food eaten by Taiwanese
尤其是台灣人吃的飯
It's still rice
到現在都還是白飯
Nutrients in it
它裡面各種營養素
are not so rich
都是沒有那麼豐富的
protein doesn't seem to be enough
蛋白質似乎是不夠
and fat
還有就是油脂
too little too few calories
也太少 熱量太少
These are all
這幾個都
Features we know
特色我們了解